老师好
Good morning, sir!
周小迪！
Dicky chow!
你看  你为什么那么脏
Just look at yourself. You're covered in dirt.
-刚才我  -不要走过来
- I just... - Don't move!
你老是找藉口
And don't give me the usual routine.
你为什么不能给我干净一点？
Why are you always so untidy?
曹主任  什么事？
What's the matter, Mr. cao?
你说！
Explain yourself!
我来跟他说  好吗？
I et me talk to him.
小迪  你怎么弄得这么脏？
Where did the dirt come from, dicky?
刚才上学的时候 不小心摔了一跤
Well, on my way to school, I slipped and fell over.
那为什么没有爸爸妈妈来送你呢？
Don't your mom or dad bring you to school?
妈妈很早就去世了  爸爸很忙
Mom died a long time ago and dad's very busy.
那你爸爸是做什么工作的？
What does your dad do?
做民工
He's a coolie.
那找个时间  袁老师和你爸爸见个面怎么样呢？
I'd like to meet him one day. Would that be possible?
我看他真的没时间
I don't think he has the time.
好吧  那等他有时间的时候你就告诉我
When he's available, then. Will you let me know?
把它拿着  快上课了  擦干净吧
Go clean up before class starts.
谢谢袁老师
Thanks, miss yuen.
我的志愿是想当大明星
I want to be a superstar.
-像谁？  -妮可基曼
Like who? Nicole Kidman.
妮可基曼片酬两千万美金
She gets $20 million for a movie.
你的志愿也是我的志愿
I wouldn't mind being her either.
我要做个大企业家
I want to be an entrepreneur.
哪一方面？
What kind of business?
哪一方面都可以  但是一定要大
Any kind, as long as it's really big.
大吃小  小被吃
Big business always pays out.
有何不可呢？
Why not?
我要做一个穷人
I want to be a poor person.
别笑了
Stop!
因为爸爸说只要有骨气
My dad says if you have integrity...
不吹牛  不打架  努力读书
Don't lie, don't fight, and study really hard...
就算穷  到哪里都会受到尊敬的
Then people will respect you even if you're poor.
别碰
Don't
不要走过来！
don't come over here!
放下！
Put it down!
回去！
Go back to your seat!
这个超级玩具狗的名字叫“长江一号”
The name of this amazing dog is cj1.
是美国  法国  德国的科学家
It was developed jointly by U.S., French and German scientists.
共同研究出来的
Imagine! Jointly developed!
-你想玩吗？  -想
- Do you want a go? - Yes, please.
滚开啦！
Back off, loser!
这个玩具狗在世界上只有两个
There are only two in the world.
另外一个在美国总统女儿的手上
The U.S. president's daughter has the other one.
-你在干嘛？  -我在吃面
- What are you doing? - Eating noodles.
你给我站出来
Stand up!
你看你矮成这个样子  吃什么都没有用了
No matter how much you eat, you are doomed to be a dwarf.
走开啦！
Now get lost!
为什么现在的学生的素质  是越来越低
The quality of the students in this place gets worse every day.
你看看  又来个奇形怪状的在这里
What have we here, another alien?
-你在干嘛？  -我在吃饭
- What are you doing? - Eating rice.
你才几岁就长得那么大块
You're just like a huge tub of lard.
有病又不去看医生
Maybe you should go see the doctor.
你还吃那么多  吓死人了！
You eat so much. It's horrible!
你们叫警察把这个怪物给枪毙
Someone call the police to shoot this monster!
吃死你  大怪物！
Fat to death! Giant monster!
你们干嘛
What are you doing?
你们欺负女孩子  不是英雄
Bullies! Heroes don't hit women.
你干嘛又跟过来？
Not you again!
别理他
Ignore him.
走了  穷鬼  我们不想跟你玩
Go away, poor boy. We don't want you around.
滚蛋吧  死穷鬼
Go away, poor boy.
你好
Hi
你也被罚站了吗？
You've been sent off the field too?”
是的
Yes
你也没带运动鞋？
did you forget your sneakers?
其实我带了  只是我故意不换而已
I brought them, but I didn't wear them on purpose.
为什么？
Why?
想陪你一起罚站
Because I wanted to be with you.
你的鞋都是破的吗？
Are all your shoes like that?
对  我所有的鞋都是破的
Yes, they are.
都是我爸爸从外面捡回来的
My dad gets them from the dump.
你爸爸可对你真好的呀
Your dad's so nice.
是的
He is, actually.
不过  我还是想要一双新的运动鞋
But I so much want a new pair...
因为我很喜欢上体育课
Because I really love sports.
我不想你有新的运动鞋
I'd like you to keep the old ones.
为什么？
Why?
我想永远陪着你罚站
Then we'd be punished together, forever.
把板子接上
Get that panel up there.
快去
Quickly!
你  动作犀利一点
You. Hurry up.
你就回去歇着吧  这里不用你了
You're no longer needed. Go home.
老板
Hey, boss?
因为这几天好热  我儿子他都睡不好
With it being so hot right now, my son can't sleep.
我要钱给他买个风扇  可不可以
I need to buy an electric fan.
让我盖下去？
Can't you keep me on?
你有钱不如先还给我吧  还想买风扇
You should be paying me back instead.
你老婆的医药费  殓葬费  都是我垫的
I paid all the bills when your wife got sick and died.
看你那副德行  一辈子都还不完了
Look at yourself. You'll die before your debts are repaid.
还要自己不吃饭  供儿子读贵族学校
You're starving yourself so your son can go to that fancy school.
我儿子也只是读普通学校  有什么分别？
If my son can go to public school, why can't yours?
也不是  不过是想让他读好一点
Well, I want him to have opportunities.
不想他将来跟我一样嘛
I don't want him to end up like me.
那你也要有能力才行嘛
But you have to have capability.
我觉得他能力很强
He's highly capable.
我说的是你
I'm talking about you, not him.
你只是个散工  凭什么？
All you have is a casual job with no prospects.
你怎么顶啊？
How are you going to cope?
-顶得了  -你顶不了
- I can manage. - You can't manage!
-顶得了  -你顶不了！
I can. You can't!
顶得了
I can manage.
去B座凿水泥地
Very well. Block b. Foundations.
谢谢老板
Thanks.
你想死他都不让你死  贱骨头
If you want to die, I can't stop you. Shame on you.
你回来了
You're back.
快点做饭  胜子饿死了
Can we have dinner? I'm starving.
你退后
Just step back a bit.
-干嘛？  -转过去
What's going on? Turn round.
来  过来
Come here.
干嘛？
What?
哇  电风扇！
An electric fan!
真的还假的？太好了！
That's so great! Is it real?
我们家终于有电风扇了
We finally have a fan!
-你先坐好  我开  -快点开  我要扇
- Now sit down and let me turn it. - Quickly, dad!
老爸  这个电风扇  又是你捡回来的？
Dad, did you find this in the garbage?
我买的
No, I bought it.
好几十块钱呢这旧风扇
It cost a lot of money.
你是不是又给人耍了？
You were ripped off!
不会  我买的时候还是好的嘛
No, it was fine when I bought it.
怎么好端端会爆了呢？
So how come it's not working now?
你大爷  你做事机伶点行不行啊？
Dumbass. Use your head next time.
谁是你大爷  你说什么？
"Dumbass"? Where did you get that from?
是我同学
A guy in my class.
你大爷是你同学？
Oh, really? Well, let me tell you...
我们虽然穷但不乱说脏话
We may be poor, but we don't use bad language.
我们不去偷  我们不去抢
We don't steal we don't Rob.
不属于自己的东西  我们不会拿
We don't take things that don't belong to us.
你要努力读书  将来做一个有用的人
You must concentrate on your studies.
我啊  就是小时候没有书念  所以现在
I didn't study at all when I was young and look where it's gotten me.
今天我们吃？
We're having an apple today?
对
Yes, we are.
等等
But put it down now.
吃完饭再吃水果
Finish your dinner first.
对了  老爸  我的运动鞋又破了
Hey, dad, my sneakers are worn out again.
你再补一补吧
Will you buy me some more?
最好再捡一双好一点的  不然要罚站
I need you to get me a better pair, or I'll be sent off the field again.
知道了  我尽力吧
Got it. Don't worry.
还在吃饭耶  打什么蟑螂啊
You're still eating! Lay off the cockroach.
吃完饭再打
You can get it after you've finished.
这个好  有进步
Nice. You've improved.
不错
Not bad.
最近有很多关于不明飞行物体  简称“UFO”的报导
There have been many sightings lately of ufos, unidentified flying objects.
动画片呢？
What happened to the cartoons?
马上来  你等一下嘛
They'll be back in a minute.
请问你能不能说说当时的情况？
Could you please tell us what happened?
我当时  我看见一个飞碟
I saw a flying object.
“咻”一下的从这边飞到那边去了
It flew from here to there with a "whew" sound.
可不可以详细说说那个飞碟？
Can you describe the object in more detail?
那个飞碟会飞的
That object could really fly!
但是飞得摇摇晃晃的
Though it wobbled a bit.
我怀疑它撞过
I suspect it had crashed before.
撞过？
Crashed?
就是撞过车  好像是撞坏了
Yes, like a car crash. It might have been broken.
我还拍了照片呢
I took a picture of ft.
先生  你用什么相机拍的呢？
What kind of camera did you use?
我那玩意儿可贵了  至于什么牌子我不方便说
It was expensive, but I can't possibly tell you the make.
那个飞碟有没有发出什么声响？
Did this particular flying object make a sound?
“咻”的一声嘛  我刚才说了
It made some "whew" sounds like I just told you.
咻一声  你听过没有？咻一声
"Whew." Do you hear me?
这两个太牛了
Unbelievable.
你干嘛乱跑？
Don't run off like that.
老爸  这个玩具叫长江一号
Dad, this is called a cj1.
同学们都有  很好玩的
Everyone at school has one. They're great!
是吗？
Really?
来  我们走了  放回去
Let's go home. Put it back.
干嘛？
What's the matter?
不如买一个吧
Why can't I have it?
我下个月发工资再买
We'll buy it after I get paid next month.
放下
Now, put it down.
放手
Let go!
你怎么那么不听话？我没钱啊
Didn't you hear me? I have no money.
就买这一次  以后  以后永远都不买了
If you buy me this, I'll never ask for anything ever again.
求求你了
I beg you.
这个？这有什么功能？
What about this one? What features does it have?
放手
Let go.
放手！
Let go!
站住
Come back!
先生  这个你买不买？
Sir? Do you wish to buy that?”
不哭了  好了
Come on, dicky. Don't cry.
好了  好孩子  好了
Stop crying now.
不要哭了
Good boy, stop crying.
小迪
Dicky.
周先生是吗？
Are you Mr. chow?
我是小迪的老师  我姓袁  你好
I'm miss yuen, dicky's teacher. Good to meet you.
袁老师  你好
Miss yuen. Good to meet you too.
小迪在学校乖不乖？
Is dicky well-behaved at school?
他在学校挺乖的
Yes, he's quite good.
他刚刚还在发脾气
He's in a really bad mood right now.
我知道  小孩子看到玩具都想要
I know. Kids just want every toy they see.
对
True.
就是我今天刚好没带钱  所以就
Just happens I didn't bring any money today, so...
小迪  去找爸爸吧
Dicky, go to your dad.
来
Come here.
-对不起  周先生  -他就是这样
- I'm sorry, Mr. chow. - Don't worry. He's like that.
其实我一直都想和您做一个家访
In fact, I'd like to do a home visit.
他也有跟我说  但是我工作比较忙
He did tell me, but I'm very busy at work...
我觉得教育孩子  单靠老师是不行的
I believe that a good education doesn't just rely on the teacher.
所以我很想很想多和你做一些沟通
That's why I'd like to involve you.
这样对他也比较好
It'll be good for him.
喔  是的
Ah, yes. I see.
小迪  老师要走了
Dicky, I need to go now.
你不要乱发脾气  要听爸爸话  知道吗？
Don't be so grumpy. And listen to your dad, okay?
知道了吗？
Okay?
-那我先走了  -好
- I must go. - Okay.
-再见  -再见
- Bye, now. - Bye, now.
小迪
Dicky.
把头转过来
I ook at me.
我有一个玩具  比长江一号更厉害
I have something way better than cj1.
你要不要看看？
Do you want to see it?
真的不要看吗？
Are you sure?
那好  我把它扔掉算了  我加班去了
In that case, I'll throw it away and get back to work.
老师再见
Goodbye, sir.
再见
Goodbye.
小芬
Fanny.
小迪  你刚刚说的  好玩东西是什么？
Where's this amazing toy, then?
你看
I ook!
这有什么好玩的？
What's so great about that?
很好玩的  你看！
It's fun. Look!
我觉得没什么好玩的
It doesn't look that fun to me.
你觉得呢？
What do you think?
其实我也觉得没什么好玩的
Actually, I agree. It's no fun.
没关系  明天见
Never mind. See you tomorrow.
你手里拿着什么东西？
What's that thing you're holding?
没有
Nothing.
一定是垃圾
It looks like rubbish.
谁说是垃圾了？
Says who?
它比长江一号还要厉害
This is way better than cj1.
啊  它叫什么名字？
So, what's it called?
它叫长江七号
It's called cj7_
算了吧  死穷鬼
Pathetic piece of crap.
我看一定是你爸爸  从垃圾桶里捡回来的
Your dad found it in the garbage.
不许说我爸爸  要不然我打你
Don't talk about my dad like that! I'm going to beat you up.
好啊
Oh, yeah?
你好
Hello.
我跟你说过多少遍？
How many times do I have to tell you?
我们虽然穷  但是不打架
We might be poor, but we don't fight.
你太不长进了
You really disappoint me.
你看看你  校服也弄破了
Look at this. Your uniform's all torn.
你为什么要打架？
What was the fight about?
同学笑我
They were laughing at me.
同学笑你什么？
What about?
笑你什么？
Well?
好
Fine.
你不说是吧
If you're not going to tell me...
是你逼我的
Then I have no choice in the matter.
说！
I ast chancel
它在动
It's moving!
有鬼
There are ghosts.
什么鬼？
(Ghosts? Where?
那个球有鬼
There. In the ball
哇  你别想转移话题  坐下
don't change the subject!
你就会欺负我没读过书
You think you can run rings around me,
你信不信我一巴掌打死你
but you're not as clever as you think.
你看看  校服破成这个样子  明天怎么上学？
Your uniform's a mess. What will you wear for school tomorrow?
我想捡都不知道去哪捡给你
Do I have to go hunt for another one?
我等一下再打你
I'll deal with you later.
有鬼！挂在那边！
There's a ghost! Hanging over there!
救命  有鬼  太恐怖了
Help! Ghost! It's horrible!
有穿红衣服的鬼挂在那边
There's a red ghost hanging there!
好怕  太恐怖了  挂在那边
Hanging! Too horrible!
别吵了！
Calm down!
这破灯掉下来嘛  什么鬼？
It's a broken lamp. Can't you see?
又怎么了
Not again!
你也像鬼
You're a ghost too.
你别再说话  不然我真的把你丢出去  听到没？
Stop shouting! I'll send you outside if you don't stop! Understand?
吃摇头丸了  你？
Are you on drugs or something?
爸爸  你干嘛？干嘛？
What are you doing?
不要  不要把我关在里面
Please don't lock me inl!
那边真的有鬼  我真的没有骗你  爸爸
There's a ghost. You have to believe me.
放我出去
I et me out!
救命  放我出去
Please let me out!
阿弥陀佛
Help me, lord.
-怕了没？  -怕了
- Learned your lesson now? - Yes, dad.
那还敢不敢调皮？
Will you behave yourself now?
不敢了  真的不敢了
I will. I really will.
我要去加班了  你自己要乖
I have to get back to work.
你快去加班  再见
Okay! Off you go. Bye!
你是从外星来的吗？
Are you from outer space?
你是不是来侵略地球的？
Have you come to invade earth?
我觉得  你应该是外星玩具狗
I think you might be an alien toy dog.
我叫小迪
My name is dicky.
你叫长江七号好不好？
Can I call you cj77?
你摇尾巴就是喜欢了？
If you wag your tail, it means you like it!
长江七号！
Cj7!
我们家的都是烂的
The apples in our house are always rotten.
为什么这个那么新鲜？
So how come this one's not?
是不是你会变魔术？
You know magic?
好甜啊  肯定是你会变魔术
Wow! It's so sweet. You really do know magic.
我发财了！
I'm going to be rich!
如果你能打败  这个地球上最凶恶的狗
If you can beat the most vicious dog on earth...
那就证明你真的是太空超人狗
Then you really are a superdog from space.
去吧
(50!
好厉害
Oh, my god!
今天考试  但是昨天一直在跟你玩  没有好好复习
I have a test today and I've been playing with you instead of studying.
我又想拿一百分  可不可以帮帮忙？
But I really want to get 100. Can you help me?
是什么？
What's that you're making?
周小迪
Dicky chow.
你干嘛戴这个眼镜上课？
Why are you wearing those glasses?
我眼睛受伤了  你要不要看看？
My eyes hurt. Do you want to take a look?
不要走过来  坐下
No, I don't. Sit down.
考试开始
Begin writing now!
对不起  有苍蝇
Sorry, sir. There was a fly.
有苍蝇
A fly?
对不起  有苍蝇
Sorry, sir. There was a fly.
今天考试的成绩出来了
I now have the results of today's test.
周小迪第一次拿一百分
And for the first time, dicky chow got 100.
-谢谢老师  -等等
- Thank you, sir! - Hold on a minute.
我要检查你的眼镜
I want to see those glasses.
刚才那个超级眼镜果然厉害
Those super-glasses were fantastic!
马上要上体育课了  我要一双超级运动鞋
It's p.E. Next, so I'll need super-sneakers!
好紧张
This is so exciting.
跳高跳得好  就是一个字
Excellence at the high jump...
天份  努力
Requires talent, hard work...
腰马合一  充足睡眠
Training, a good night's sleep...
还有尊敬老师
And finally, respect for your teacher.
这是我创的记录
This is my personal record.
到现在还没有人可以跳得过去
So far no one has bettered it
老师  我今天有新的运动鞋
I have new sneakers today, sir.
老师  他刚刚好像破了你的记录
Sir! He just broke your record.
小迪  小孩子是不需要跳那么高的
Dicky, it doesn't ring true
那样是很不合情理的
that a kid can jump that high.
你乖乖地再跳一次吧
Be a good boy and do it again.
周小迪  你穿的是什么鞋？
Dicky chow. What are those shoes you're wearing?
不关你的事！
It's none of your business!
你太过份了
This is too much.
是你们逼我的
You drove me to this.
下来！
Come down!
-小迪  你疯了？  -我
Dicky! Are you out of your mind? I
那边  快点  抓住他
over here. Catch him!
小迪  回头是岸
Come to your senses, dicky.
袁老师  苦海无涯
Miss yuen, bitterness, like the sea, is boundless.
小迪
Dicky!
周小迪  你跳那么高干什么？下来
Dicky chow! How can you jump so high? Come down this minute!
这么高难度你也睡得着？
How on earth can you sleep like that?
起床了你  上学了
Wake up. It's nearly time for school.
叫你自己要乖的嘛  每次都睡过头
What do I have to do to get you up in the morning?
作梦？
It was all a dream?
是真的
You're real.
我去上学了
I'm getting ready right now!
老爸  今天考试我要拿一百分
Dad, I'm going to get 100 on the exam today.
啊？
What?
我要拿一百分！
I'm going to get 100!
就凭你？
Really?
就凭我  一百分！
Yes! All on my own! 100!
那就好
That's great.
如果你能打败  这个地球上最凶恶的狗
If you can beat the most vicious dog on earth...
那就证明你真的是太空超人狗
Then you really are a superdog from space.
去吧
(50!
走啊！
Run!
刚才是怎么回事？
So, what happened back there?
你不是太空超人狗吗？
You're supposed to be the superdog from space.
你是不是在装傻？
Don't tell me you were just pretending.
我不是在和你开玩笑
Seriously.
今天考试  我要拿一百分
I have to get 100 on the exam.
你一定有什么法宝  拿出来帮帮忙
I need you to work your magic for me.
别玩了  我是很认真的
Come on, now. Please! I'm not joking.
法宝  拿出来
You have to give me magic weapons.
时间到
Time's up.
我还没开始
What? But I haven't started yet.
你怎么拿着一坨屎？
What's with the turd?
屎  不会吧？
Turd? It's not that!
不信你试试看
Shows how much you know!
你敢耍我！
You set me up!
我跟你拼了
I'm going to kill you!
最后一次机会  给我法宝
Give me the magic weapons now!
你为什么
Why, you...
你
You
老师  你听我说
Please, sir. Can I say something?
你不要说了
No, you can't.
你这个夫暇
You are a poor student.
低俗  人面兽心的学生
You are always dirty, and you are very wicked.
没有品位到这种境界
You discredit the school.
还有什么好说的
There's nothing more to say.
把他弄干净
Now clean him up!
七仔？
Cj77?
快点出来
Please come out.
我怎么会生你气呢？
Why would I be mad at you?
我们是好朋友嘛
We're good friends.
大便对我来说是小菜一碟
The turd wasn't important.
我有什么大便没见过呢？
I've seen it all before.
这件事已经随风而过  没事
Let's just forget it ever happened. Okay?
其实我是很疼你的  你知道吗？
In fact, I love you very much. Do you know that?
七仔？过来
Cj77 come here.
乖
Closer!
我捅死你
I'm going to stab you to death!
你这个太空垃圾狗  低科技又低级趣味
Rubbish dog from space. You're low-tech and boring.
现在同学笑我  老师冤枉我  你是活该的
I got blamed and laughed at. And all because of you.
你这么差劲就应该坦白  我还以为你很厉害
If you're just an animal, then say so! Don't pretend you have magic powers!
但是它没有说过它很厉害啊
But did it ever say that”
难道是我误会它了？
did I get it wrong?
是不是我错了？
Have I made a mistake?
我就知道是我错了
I know I've made a mistake!
等一等
Wait!
喂！  等一等
Hey! Wait!
等一等
Wait!
干嘛？
Dicky! What's happened?
七仔不见了
Cj7 has disappeared.
你看
I ook.
七仔？
Cj77?
对不起  我很想你
I'm sorry. I missed you so much.
我以为以后再也见不到你了
I thought I'd never see you again.
你不生我的气就好了
And you're not angry with me.
原来你们两个认识
You two already met?
这只是玩具？
Is it a toy?
是啊
Yes, it is.
会走会跳会眨眼睛
And it can walk and move its eyes?
你从哪边拿的？
Where did you get it?
同学借我玩的
Someone at school lent it to me.
它的盖子呢？
Where's the cover?
从哪里充电？
Where do the batteries go?
不用电  是高科技
It doesn't need them. It's high-tech.
这种高科技的玩具  我还真没见过
I've never seen anything like it before.
你看到了没有？
Did you see that?
看到
Yes, I did.
弹力这么强
It's all bendy.
不要弄了  还要还给同学
Don't! I have to give it back soon.
怕什么
It's fine.
-老爸  你干嘛？  -没事
- What are you doing, dad?” - Nothing!
我就说没事  它又还原了
See, I told you it'd be fine. It gets its shape back. Look!
真好玩
This is fun.
不要再弄了  够了
No more squeezing it! That's enough!
现在科技这么高
Everything is high-tech nowadays.
我们这些没读过书的人
Basically there's no future
我看这一辈子也就这个样子了
for uneducated people like us.
老爸  我不想骗你  其实
Dad, I don't want to lie to you, so...
七仔是你给我的那个球变出来的
Cj7 came out of the ball you gave me.
它是从外太空来的
It came from outer space.
我跟你说过多少次
How many times do I have to tell you?
我们虽然穷  但是我们不说谎话
We might be poor, but we don't lie...
也不打架
We don't fight...
不属于自己的东西  我们不会拿
And we don't take things that don't belong to us.
要努力读书  将来做一个有用的人才
Study hard and be a useful person in the future.
好热
It's so hot.
最热的这天它无缘无故地又会动了  真是幸运
Well, I'll be... the hottest night and it starts to work. Lucky, or what?
我上学了
I'm off to school now.
-饭盒带了没？  -带了
- Have you got your lunch box? - Yes, I have.
喂  考试考得怎么样？
Hey. How was the exam?
你头顶干嘛变成红色的？
How come your head's gone red?
你今天好像没精打采的
You don't look so good today.
是不是昨天晚上没睡好？
Didn't you sleep last night?
你回去多睡会吧
Get inside and go to sleep.
站住
You! Stop!
你书包里面是什么东西？
What's that thing inside your bag?
没有
Nothing.
检查书包
I need to check your schoolbag!
检查什么书包？
What for?
我要查就查
I don't have to tell you that.
放手
Let go!
这是什么东西？
What's that?
给我看看
I et me see.
给我  给我看看
Give it to me! Let me see first!
给我  不要拉
Give it to me! Don't pull!
-抓住它  -追
(Get it!
什么鬼东西啊？
What is this weird thing?
别碰它  还给我！
Don't touch it! Give it back to me!
拿工具箱过来
(Set the tool box!
把它打开来看看
Open it up and look inside.
来
Here
放开它
let him go!
不行
Can't do it.
直接来吧
Try this.
求求你  不要这样子
No! Don't do that!
锯不开
It's not working.
怎么可能？
How is that possible?
你干嘛抢我东西？
You won't do that to my thing!
又怎么样？打我啊
So what”? Going to hit me?
我就打你
You won't know what's hit you!
放开他
Let him go!
You let him go.
你先放开我
You let me go first.
我不想打架
I don't want a fight.
不要逼我！
Don't force me to do this!
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
我没事  谢谢
I'm fine. Thank you.
不用谢
You're welcome.
你们干嘛？
What's going on here?
你们为什么打架？说！
Why were you fighting? Tell me!
不说就全罚站
You're going to stand here until you tell me!
七仔！
Cj7!
我就知道你没事
I knew you'd be okay!
不要这样
Stop. Don't.
乖
Good boy.
喂  这到底是什么啊？
What is that thing”?
你看  七仔  坐下
Look! Cj7, sit!
好聪明
That's cool.
它还会干些什么？
What else does it do?
七仔  高兴！
Cj7, happy face!
生气！
Angry face!
伤心！
Sad face!
看到美女！
Saw a pretty lady!
家里着火！
Your apartment's on fire.
中了彩票！
But you just won the lottery!
全家死光！
Oops! The whole family is dead.
考试一百分！
You've got 100 on the exam!
好厉害
Wicked
你看
I ook!
哇！放烟花！
Wow, fireworks!
你的玩具到底在哪里买的？
Where did you get it?
对  我也想买一个
I want one too.
这个是秘密
I can't tell you that.
不过我还是要谢谢你
But I want to thank you
没有把这件事情告诉曹主任
for not telling Mr. cao about this.
那当然了
Of course not!
小孩子的事情  才不告诉大人呢
We don't discuss our business with adults.
-一言为定  -一言为定！
- You have my word! - You have my word!
你真的满厉害的  要不要加入我们柔道队？
Hey, you're amazing. Do you want to be on our judo team?
不用了  他们都笑我
They'd all make fun of me.
谁还敢笑你
They wouldn't dare.
你们还会笑她吗？
Would you make fun of her?
你看  我儿子考试拿了一百分
Look at this. My son got 100 on his exam.
你孩子真了不起
That's a great kid!
对
Yes!
-你看  -滚开
- Look! - Get away!
他拿了一百分
He got 100.
老板  我儿子考试真的拿一百分了
Boss. My kid got 100 on his exam.
他一定是作弊
So he cheated.
你为什么这么说？
What makes you say that?
我儿子这么聪明  他作弊才考到六十分
My son's really smart, but even he can't pass without cheating.
你儿子考一百分没有作弊？  谁信啊？贱骨头
So how can your son get 1007? Hard to believe, dickhead.
你胡说吧
You're not serious.
墨水的颜色不一样  明明是零分
Look at the ink. He got zero
自己改成一百分的  骗谁啊
and changed it to 100. He's a liar.
但是我认识他这么久  他不像是这种人
But he's not like that. I know him better.
你儿子作弊
Your son cheated.
-我不准你这么说他  -你儿子作弊！
- I can't let you say that. - He cheated!
你再说我打你
I'll hit you if you say that again.
你儿子作弊
Your son cheated.
你打我？
You hit me? Just you try!
你儿子作弊  你打我？
Your son cheated! You hit me?
你以后不用上班了
You're fired!
你儿子作弊！
Your son cheated!
快进去
Quick!
进去
(Set inside.
你老老实实告诉我  你考试是不是作弊？
Tell the truth. Did you cheat on your exam?
没有
No, I didn't.
你考了零鸭蛋  结果自己改成一百分  是不是？
I think you got zero, then altered it to 100. Is that right?
是
Yes
我改了分又不是作弊  就是怕你不高兴
but that's not the same as cheating. I didn't want you to be disappointed.
你有没有搞错？
What's wrong with you?
我供你读书  很辛苦的
It's so tough to send you to that school.
对不起  老爸
I'm sorry, dad.
我跟你说了多少次  我们虽然穷
I'll say it again. Even though we're poor...
啊呀！  我知道了
Okay! I know!
你好烦  别再说这些了好不好？
You're so annoying. Can you stop going on about it?
反正都已经改了  你能怎么样？
I changed it. So what?
没什么事  我就走了
If there's nothing else, I'm leaving.
干嘛？
What are you doing?
你想怎么样？
Why are you taking my things?
你不用心读书  我不准你再跟它玩
If you can't work hard, then you don't get to play.
-还给我  -不给
- Give it back to me! - No_
你凭什么拿我东西？
Why are you taking my stuff?
凭什么？  就凭我是你老爸  行不行？
Why"? Because I'm your father! And I can!
那你就是以大欺小  我没你这种老爸
You're bullying me. I don't have a dad like youl!
你总是拿零鸭蛋  我还没你这种儿子
You always get zeros. I don't have a son like you.
我不要你管我
I eave me alone!
你再说一次
Say it again!
我永远都不要你管我
I eave me alone forever!
好
Okay!
你有能耐就凭真本事
If you can use your own
考一个六十分回来给我看看
brains to get over 60...
那我就永远不管你
Then I'll leave you alone forever!
-你说的  -我说的！
- It's a deal! - It's a deal!
我就考给你看  到时候不要赖皮
I'm going to get that grade. Just watch me!
少吹了  考试不是靠嘴巴  零鸭蛋
We'll see about that, zero hero!
你不要那么嚣张  我一定考给你看
That's not fair! I'll show you!
你永远都不要再管我
Don't bother me anymore!
你看什么看
What are you looking at?
-周先生  -袁老师
- Mr. chow. - Miss yuen.
-有什么事吗？先进来说  -不要了
- Is something wrong? Please come in. - I won't, thanks.
小迪忘了带饭  你可以帮我交给他吗？
But dicky forgot his lunch box today. Could you see that he gets it?
好  你先进来吧  我叫他们开门
Sure. Let me ask someone to open the gate.
不用  我这个样子给人看见了  我怕同学会笑他
No, please don't. If his classmates see me, he'll never live it down.
怎么会呢？
How come?
-我先走了  -等一下
I have to go. “Wait.
小迪都和我说了
Dicky told me everything.
他只是闹闹别扭
He was just being temperamental.
如果你不介意的话  今天晚上让他和我回家
If you'd allow it, he could come to my house after school.
我会和他好好谈一谈
We can talk about what happened.
正好明天考试也可以帮他温习功课
And there's another exam tomorrow, so I can help him to review.
觉得呢？
What do you think?
那太感谢你了
Oh, thank you. Thank you!
-不客气  没什么的  -不  我真的很感谢你
- You're welcome. It's nothing at all. - I appreciate this so much.
-这真的没什么的  只是小事情  -不是小事情
- It's just a small thing. Nothing, really. - It's not nothing.
因为我
The thing is...
自己没有能力给他什么  心里一直都很内疚
I can't give him very much myself, and that makes me feel very guilty.
现在你肯这样帮忙  我真的不知道该怎么报答你
But if you were to help him study, I could never repay you.
你不用报答我什么  这是我应该做的
You really don't have to. It's the least I can do.
那小迪我就交给你了
Then I'll leave him in your hands.
好  你放心交给我吧
Sure. You just leave dicky to me.
-谢谢  -不客气
Thank you. You're welcome.
今天老板脾气好吗？
How's the boss feeling today?
你还敢回来啊？
You dare to come back?
我要吃饭啊
I have to. I need to eat.
我知道我口臭  反正是同乡  就这么算了
I know I have a big mouth, but I think we understand each other.
什么？
What?
我不应该当着那么多人面说你儿子
I shouldn't have said that about your son.
收一下这红包算了
Let's forget it. Here.
这
Well
-但是他真的作弊  -谁不作弊啊？
- but he really did cheat. - Who doesn't, sometimes?
你儿子这么聪明  将来一定出人头地
The kid is very smart. I know he'll be successful
要是那样就谢天谢地了
I pray to god that you're right.
拿去给他买东西吃吧
So take it and buy him some candy.
你不用给那么多
Hey! This is far too much.
行了  给他交书本费  交学费好了  赶快开工
Use it for books, then. Or school fees. But now get back to work.
今天我走运了
Today must be my lucky day.
想不到你能及格
I thought you'd never pass.
很好
(Ood.
谢谢曹主任
Thanks, Mr. cao.
干嘛？
What's happening?
安全带
Where's your safety belt?
干嘛？
What's going on here?
救命
Help!
把手伸过来
Give me your hand!
小心点  伸过来
Reach out! Give me your hand!
干嘛还不搬过去？快点
Why haven't these been moved?
干什么？小心点
What was that”? Hey! Be careful!
对不起
I'm so sorry.
小迪  你出来一下
Dicky, you have to come with me.
小迪  这里就是你家？
Is this your house, dicky?
你胜子饿不饿  要不要吃东西？
Are you hungry? Do you want to eat?
小迪  老师要告诉你一件事情
Dicky, I'm going to tell you something.
你爸爸他出意外去世了
There was a terrible accident, and your dad passed away.
小迪  有很多事情是人不能控制的  你知道吗？
There are some things we can't control. Do you understand?
老师  你不要说了  我要睡觉了
Don't talk anymore, miss. I want to sleep.
你先回去
Please leave me.
小迪
Dicky, open the door.
对不起
I'm sorry.
袁老师
Miss yuen.
我很累了
I'm very tired.
我真的要睡觉了
I need to sleep.
小迪
Dicky.
老爸他不会不理我的
My dad won't leave me alone.
等我睡醒之后  他就会回来的
He'll be home when I wake up.
我要睡觉了
I need to sleep now.
小迪
Dicky.
爸爸
Dad.
为什么不换衣服睡觉？
Why aren't you in your pajamas?
怎么了？
Hey. What's up?
爸爸  你不要不管我
Dad, don't ever leave me.
我以后会听话的
I'll listen to you...
我要好好读书
I'll study hard...
不吹牛
Won't lie
不打架
I won't fight...
将来做一个对社会有用的人
And one day I'll be a really useful person.
那就乖
That's good.
七仔！
Cj7!
你好吗？
How are you?
这是什么声音？
What's that noise?
我也不知道
Yeah, what is it?
你干嘛这么累？
Why are you so tired, cj7?
老爸  它怎么回事？
What's happened to him, dad?
会不会没电了？
Maybe the batteries have run out.
没电怎么会这样子
It wouldn't look like that!
高科技嘛
But it's very high-tech.
新学期又要开始了
The new term starts soon..
学校特地在开学前搞了个旅行
And we have a picnic before going back.
同学们都很开心
Everybody's very happy.
暴龙同学不再打架了
Storm dragon doesn't fight anymore...
因为他喜欢上了一个人
Because he's fallen in love.
但美娇却喜欢我
Maggie likes me best...
其实我爱的人是小芬女
But my love is Fanny.
小芬女也很爱我的
And she loves me very much too!
蛋塔头总是抢我东西
Johnny always takes what's mine.
我就告诉老师  看你们能好多久
Maybe he'll stop when I tell the teacher about him.
同学们心里面都有自己喜欢的人
Every pupil has his own true love.
我爸爸也不例外
And so has my dad.
真是太神奇了  上次我明明
It's just amazing. When we saw you
看见你躺在医院里面已经
in the hospital you appeared to be quite...
已经死了嘛  但是后来又没事了
Dead, yes. But now I'm right as rain.
我自己都不明白  医生也解释不了
Not even the doctors can explain it.
那你现在觉得自己身体怎么样？
And how have you been since then?
我最近身体有点问题
Well, I do have a bit of a problem.
什么样的问题？
What kind of problem?
我觉得我好英俊
I'm far too handsome.
满好笑的
Very funny.
我是说真的
I mean it.
让人喜欢自己不是很容易
It's not easy to win a girl over...
但老爸是不会放弃的
Especially if you're not that funny.
他是我的大英雄
But dad won't give up. He's my hero.
袁老师  你敢说我不英俊吗？  你再看清楚一点
You don't think I'm handsome, miss yuen? You can't be serious.
还有你  七仔
I'm so lucky that I still have you, cj7.
自从你睡觉后
Every day, while you sleep...
我每天都会先闭上眼睛数三声
I close my eyes and count to three
希望睁开眼睛  就会看见你醒过来
hoping when I look again, you'll wake.
我那么有诚意  你就醒一醒吧
I want you back so much. Where are you, cj77?
一  二  三
One, two, three...